<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Scoping on UNICEF Data Science &amp; A.I. Toolkit</title><link>https://unicef.github.io/ooi-toolkit-ds/03-scoping/</link><description>Recent content in Scoping on UNICEF Data Science &amp; A.I. Toolkit</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Creative Commons BY-SA 4.0. Site theme adapted from UNICEF Inventory theme.</copyright><atom:link href="https://unicef.github.io/ooi-toolkit-ds/03-scoping/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>What if we don’t have the right data to solve the problem?</title><link>https://unicef.github.io/ooi-toolkit-ds/03-scoping/what-if-we-dont-have-the-right-data.adoc/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://unicef.github.io/ooi-toolkit-ds/03-scoping/what-if-we-dont-have-the-right-data.adoc/</guid><description>This has to do with inherent limitations that may exist in the information collected. At some point, no technology or analysis will help you further. Considering whether the right data exists is critical at the early project stage. You may want to create contingencies to pivot towards collecting better data to answer the question. Or, if the data simply does not exist or is impractical to collect, revert to the original question of interest and redefine the project scope.</description></item><item><title>What if we don’t like the results?</title><link>https://unicef.github.io/ooi-toolkit-ds/03-scoping/what-if-we-dont-like-the-results.adoc/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://unicef.github.io/ooi-toolkit-ds/03-scoping/what-if-we-dont-like-the-results.adoc/</guid><description>This is when the results of the project are not those anticipated by the end user. This can be a function of not having the right data, poor model inputs or poor model predictions in specific scenarios. The possibility that the project might lead to poor results should be discussed among the project stakeholders. This addresses differences in how individuals might accept the results of the project and reveal inherent biases individuals might have.</description></item><item><title>When is the project over?</title><link>https://unicef.github.io/ooi-toolkit-ds/03-scoping/when-is-the-project-over.adoc/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://unicef.github.io/ooi-toolkit-ds/03-scoping/when-is-the-project-over.adoc/</guid><description>This is about aligning expectations and gets to why the project was initiated in the first place. Think about what the final deliverable is and work iteratively backward. Gather stakeholder input and identify reasons the project could end. Setting aside obvious failures, such as lack of funding or losing interest, focus should be on the needs to be delivered and how to conclude the project. Many projects will require ongoing support and maintenance, but this should be clarified up front.</description></item><item><title>Who does the problem affect?</title><link>https://unicef.github.io/ooi-toolkit-ds/03-scoping/who-does-the-problem-affect.adoc/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://unicef.github.io/ooi-toolkit-ds/03-scoping/who-does-the-problem-affect.adoc/</guid><description>This is about identifying the end users. Identify the people who will be affected by the problem and incorporate them into the discussion of problem articulation. This can mean small group or focus group discussions if they are representative of a larger group of people. Understand how these people will be affected by the project. One approach to think about this is to have a solution trial run. Assuming you can answer the problem, ask yourself if you can use the answer and whose life will change as a result.</description></item><item><title>Why is the problem important?</title><link>https://unicef.github.io/ooi-toolkit-ds/03-scoping/why-is-the-problem-important.en.adoc/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://unicef.github.io/ooi-toolkit-ds/03-scoping/why-is-the-problem-important.en.adoc/</guid><description>This section is about problem definition. This sets the expectations for why a project should be undertaken in the first place. Identifying the importance of the problem before starting will help optimize how company resources are used. Relatedly, you will want to answer:
Why does this problem matter? Is this a new problem or has it been solved already? In this effort, you will want to engage with the different collaborators, both technical and non-technical, to understand how each person sees the problem.</description></item></channel></rss>